Sedric Ouambo Silatchom

https://sedricouambo.github.io/sedric-portfolio

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A professional Certified Developer, with more than 5 years of experience as software developer and teacher, combined with a solid training in computer science and an enthusiastic spirit, a strong interest in innovation and an ability to quickly and adapt to new technologies, I am able to work effectively in agile mode, autonomously or as a team perfectly in French and English. I have a strong knowledge of collecting client needs, a strong knowledge of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), data structures and proven skills in teaching, coding techniques and computer program design.

WORK EXPERIENCE

La Cité College, Ottawa, Canada.

Contractual Professor of React et Next.js.

05/2024 - to present

- Developed a website using React and Next.js frameworks to present course content and demos, enabling learners to progress quickly in their studies.
- Introduce and explain React components, routing with Next.js, and best practices for front-end development.
- Taught learners how to develop modern, responsive, mobile-first web applications using the React and Next.js frameworks.
- Supervise students in managing their own projects, provide weekly feedback, and assess their work.

CEPI - La Cité College, Ottawa, Canada.

Python Developer.

05/2023 - 08/2023

- Collaborated with team colleagues to build an Python API to facilitate the use of Pepper and NAO robots functionalities.
- Crafted comprehensive documentation describing the procedures for managing the motion, sound and visual sensors of the robots, allowing a 30% reduction in the time users use to manage robots.
- Developed Python scripts to allow robots to run a simulated abduction at Collège La Cité, during staff academic year, which increased participant satisfaction by 50%.

Ministry of Secondary Education, Cameroon.

Software Developer.

01/2017 - 05/2022

- Participate in developing an application for the management and deliberation of official examinations, which will reduce the waiting time for examination results by over 50%.
- Participate in the development of a website for the census of ministry staff in decentralized services using PHP and MySQL.
- In collaboration with colleagues, design and implement the KSCHOOL application for school management at the Technical High School of Santchou, using Java and PostgreSQL.

CONTACT

- · +1 819-319-9747
- ouambosedric@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/sedricouambo

My Portfolio:

https://sedricouambo.github.io/sedric-portfolio

SKILLS

Hard Skill:

- Coding (Advanced)
- Debugging (Experienced)
- Software Design and Testing
- · Web and mobile Development

Programming Languages:

· C#, · Python, · Java, · Swift, · Kotlin

Web technologies:

- · HTML, · CSS, · JavaScript
- · React, · Next.js, · Express.js
- · Node.js, · PHP; · Django

Databases:

- · MySQL, · SQL Server, · MongoDB
- · Cassandra, · PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

La Cité College

Ontario College Diploma Computer Programming

Ottawa, Canada 09/2022 - 04/2024

University of Dschang

Bachelor of Computer Science

(WES Equivalence available)

Dschang, Cameroon 10/2009 - 07/2012

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Associate in Python Programming (PCAP).
- Android Certified Developer
- Workplace rescue worker.